JOHN SABOTTA 6547 42nd Ave SW, Apt. 14 Seattle, WA 98118 phone (206)849-9226

e-mail: john@johnsabotta.com

Illustrator and graphic designer since 1984 - familiar with both PC and MAC environments and used to critical deadline production work. Over ten years experience with Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Quark Xpress, and Adobe PageMaker. Web design programs I use on a daily basis include Macromedia Dreamweaver, Fireworks, and Flash. I create original artwork using either digital or conventional media, from cartoon graphics to realistic illustration. Also familiar with layout and production work for print, including four-color advertisements, brochures, catalogs and publications

Employment History

2002 - 2004

Graphic Artist and Web Designer - Cantrall and Associates

Web and print design for Cantrall and Associates, a full service associate management company in Seattle. Clients included the American Orthopaedic Foot and Ankle Society, the Eastern Orthopaedic Society and many others. Production work and advertisement design and layout for the Foot and Ankle International, the official scientific journal of the AOFAS.

2001 - 2002

Graphic Artist and Web Designer - Eproductions And Solutions,

Web design and print graphics for business clients such as trumusic.com. Four color brochure design, institutional advertising and illustration. Seattle, WA.

1997 to 1999

Graphic Artist - Western Video Services

In-house graphic artist for Bellevue video duplication and editing house. Used Lightwave 3D and Adobe After Effects to create video animation for clients, as well as video tape packaging design and in-house advertisng art.

1993 to 1997

Art Director - Video Only, Seattle Corporate Office

For this major electronics retailer I designed and produced weekly full-page and tabloid newspaper advertisements for 14 West Coast locations. Worked with an all-Macintosh electronic publishing system, using Quark Xpress and Adobe Photoshop, and coordinated with newspapers for ad placement and ad delivery. Created informational wall posters, point-of-purchase displays, direct mail material and in-store price tags.

1990 to 1993

Graphic and Video Effects Artist - Pacific Communications (PACCOM)

Olympia, WA. Jobs included work for the Washington State Department of Transportation, the Washington Association of School Administrators, Yardbirds Shopping Centers, and many others. Most projects used Adobe Photoshop to create original video graphics and animation sequences for video productions. Other projects included four color brochures and video sleeves and labeling

1984 to 1990

Screen print Production Artist - Professional Towel Company

Olympia, WA. Design work and Macintosh illustration for company's line of custom screen-printed towels. I created concepts and production art, adapted client art (sometimes from faxes or business cards!) and scheduled the design and production of final art for dye-based multi-color screen-printing projects, as well as being in charge of the darkroom and stat camera. Assignments included work for Northrop, Apple Computer and Nike.

Freelance experience

1990 to present

freelance graphic artist and illustrator

My work has covered almost every aspect of graphic design and illustration, including web site design, preparation of graphics for web sites, four-color brochures and maps, original illustration, newspaper advertising, logo design and graphics and animation for video production. Web sites I have designed include:

http://www.ptforkids.org/ http://www.clinicient.com/

http://www.pugetorthorehab.com/home.htm

http://www.womancareinc.com/http://www.stricklandpt.com/

For local Seattle video production house Cardinal Media, I created title graphics and animation for a series of traffic safety public service spots, and several of his traffic and railroad safety videos. Highlights included simulating railroad stopping distances in Lightwave 3D for Cardinal Media's "Roll Call: Operation Lifesaver" video, and using After Effects to make a dog "talk" for a Washington Traffic Safety Commission Video.

In 1999 I was included in an Emerald City Gold Award for "United Way of Snohomish County: It's Time" by Cardinal Media, and two Emerald City Silver Awards for "Roll Call: Operation Lifesaver" and "A Safer State At .08" In addition, "United Way of Snohomish County: It's Time" won a Silver Award at the 1999 Worldfest Flagstaff International Film Festival. In addition, I created VHS video packaging for several Cardinal Media films, as well as their logo design.

Designed and illustrated a video box for a proposed Boeing Museum of Flight historical video - "The B-29 Story"

Animation in Macromind Director for the Microsoft Network "MINT" on-line magazine, in collaboration with internationally acclaimed illustrator Aidan Hughes. Also with Aidan Hughes, I produced animation and designed effects for a 20 second station identification spot for the Locomotion cable channel of Florida.

Designed book covers for Peanut Butter Press of Seattle, produced magazine cover illustrations for local alternative and literary magazines, including Throwrug and Koon Woon's Chrysanthemum

Education

Art Institute of Seattle - graduated in 1983 receiving a degree in Commercial Trained in illustration, paste-up, layout, design skills and airbrush rendering, with instructors such as Jim Scott, William Cummings and Fred Griffin

University of Washington - graduated in 1981 with a Bachelor of Arts degree. Concentrated on graphic arts and media production, taking courses in film and video production, fine art, drawing and painting.